<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-electric-chair</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85032490/1887-04-17/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=Death+Dynamo+Electric+Chair+Capital+Punishment&amp;r=0.032,0.361,1.353,0.767,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          DEATH IN THE DYNAMO
          "How would you uso electricity?"
          "Just seo here," said Dr. Southwick,
          jumping up and .seating himself, in an arm
          chair. "Tho condemned man cansifc natur
          ally in a chair like this, placo his liands on
          the metal arms and converse with those
          around him. Tho metal plates would ba
          connected with a powerful d3namo and at
          tho proper moment somebody in another
          room would press a button, closo tho current
          and tho fatal shock would pass through tho
          body of the subject. Tho chargo would go
          straight through tho heart and lungs and
          penetrate the system, death instantly result
          ing. Tho expense of the apparatus with which
          to execute by electricity ia this city would
          bo about $150. Connection cculd bo made
          with the electric light station, and tho ex
          pense of an execution thereafter would bo of
          littlo consequence. It would not cost any
          more than a cigar to kill a condemned man
          after that. It would not bo necessary to
          maintain extensive and powerful machinery
          in nil tho prisons, anil it would bo vastly
          cheaper than hanging."
          "You believe then in electricity?'
          "Electricity Ls tho coming power. Death
          is instantaneous and tho body i not defaced.
          There is not tho morbidness of n hanging,
          which is a relic cf barbarism. Just seo a
          recent execution here Heman's I think it
          was when tho hanged man breathed fifteen
          minutes afteV the drop fell. If that is in
          stantaneous death then I would rather havo
          u lingering death."

          Regarding tho machinery to Iw used
          Senator llcl.lillan says: "Theso 'executions
          could take place in tho jail proper, in a room
          set apart for that purpose, with no appli
          ances save that of a chair, with tuo nana
          rest of each arm properly connected with
          an electric machine, in which tho condemned
          might bo seated and tho connection made by
          strapping a hand to the hand rest on each
          chair. There can bo no difficulty whatever
          in procuring a current of electricity of suffi
          cient strength to paralyze tho muscles of
          tho heart by this method. Indeed, tho cur
          rent that is used in this city for electric
          lighting purposes is of sufficient strength to
          absolutely dismember the body of nay human
          being, but a current of electricity of suffi
          cient strength to cause instantaneous death
          by passing from hand to hand through the
          heart wi'l not mark the body in tho least."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075267/1888-12-13/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Electrical+Electric+Chair+Capital+Punishment+Killing+Electricity+murderers+lightning&amp;r=-0.073,0.021,0.425,0.241,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          A PLAN PROPOSED
          gow Will Electrical Execu
          tions Be Accomplished?
          TlE LAST THING IN KILLING.
          How Various Nations Do Their Criminals
          to Death--New TYok State the Flrat
          commeunty to Adapt the Newest Thing
          in Capital PlUnihment.
          After Jan. 1, 1880, murderers in New York
          sate will depart this life on a streak of light
          ing. Any man who has been sentenced to
          death will go off. so quick that he won't
          know anything about it. The subject of
          putting murderers to death by electricity has
          been agitated in the Empire state for more
          than a year.
          After mature deliberation it was concluded
          that hanging would have to go.
          Hanging has been the fashionable mode of
          punishment for centuries, but a commission
          *appointed by Governor Hill concluded that it
          was too harrowing. They made a number
          of experiments, and finally decided upon
          electricity. A bill was passed by the legis
          lature, but-no provision was made as to the
          way the fluid was to be applied. Finally the
          Medico-legal society took the matter Uo, ap
          pointed a commission, and the result was
          that a particular form of applying the elec
          tricity was suggested. This way of killing
          off the refuse population will probably be
          used in New York state hereafter. Three
          ways of applying the fatal electricity were
          proposed, but none of them answered the
          purpose. One was passing the electri.
          iots city from wrist to
          wrist through the
          body, another
          was passing the
          current from the
          head to one of the
          wrists, the third
          Swas topassthecmu
          rent completely
          t through the prison.
          S1 etr's body from head
          to foot.
          c c m The objections to
          A CURRENT IN THE BRAIn these methods were
          that the prisoner might have convulsions.
          It was desired, of course, to take the utmost
          care of the prisoner. He was to die as pleas
          antly as possible. Then the attendant under
          this method might make a mistake and be
          struck himself.
          The commission finally concluded that the
          best way would be to have the current pass
          through the hoad from the top to the back of
          the neck. One electrode is fitted to the top
          of the prisoner's head, another placed in con
          tact with the small of his back. The top
          electrode connects with the positive pole, the
          bottom with the negative pole. A leathern
          rest holds the prisoner's head and bands
          keep him from moving. The current, in go
          ing from one electrode to another, does not
          keep in a straight line, but spreads out and
          goes through the entire brain. It resembles
          somewhat a bundle of faggots tied at the two
          ends and swelling out in the middle. The seat
          of consciousness being in the brain, and the
          headquarters for all the nerves being located
          there, it is of course as plain as day that,
          when an electro-motive force of 8, 30 volts
          is applied, the prisoner is bound to die. The
          great beauty of this system is that the pris
          oners don't know it either.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84025891/1895-09-07/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Lizzie+Halliday+Lunatic+Asylum+Murder+Electricity&amp;r=0.063,0.173,1.325,0.752,0
        </id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016758/1899-06-01/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Death+Chair+Penalty+Capital+Punishment+Murder&amp;r=0.288,-0.057,0.943,0.535,0
        </id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028140/1901-10-29/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Repentance+Czolgosz+Electric+Chair+Electrocuted+Deadly+Current&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.402,-0.464,1.547,1.547,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          NO WORD OF REPENTANCE
          With Brute Courage Czolgosz Met De
          -th
          In the Electric Chair.
          Cowardice Quivered on His Lips, But Unsustained by Prayer or Hope of Eter
          nity He Felt the Mask of Death Upon His Face and Passed to Oblivion,
          Hated and Despised.
          Auburn, N. Y., Oct 20.-(Spl.)-Loon
          F. Czolgosz, alias Fred Nieman, was
          successfully electrocuted at Auburn
          prison this morning. He was pro
          nouncod dead at 7:10:15 a. in.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1903-10-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Chair+Fifteen+Minutes+Van+Wormers+Electrocuted+Willis+Frederick+Burton+Electric&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.082,-0.062,0.679,0.679,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          3 VAN WORMERS DIE IN THE CHAIR IN 15 MINUTES
          The Brothers Are Electrocuted One
          After the Other with Marvellous
          i Speed Without a Hitch in the Triple
          Tragedy Each Displaying Nerve
          I Willis the Eldest Was the First tcTDie
          Then Came Frederick the Youngest
          I 1 and Burton Most Composed and De
          l termined of All Was the Last
          I
          I I
          QUICK WORK OF DEATH SHOCKS
          WILLIS VAN WORMER entered the deathchamber at
          113430 The current was turned into his body one
          minute later He was dead at 1137
          FRBDBRICK VAN WORMER entered the deathchamber at
          11413O At 1142 the current was turned on He was
          declared dead at 114330
          I
          BURTON VAN WORMER entered the deathchamber at
          1147 The currant wai turned on at 114730 He was
          declared dead at 114830
          lbe actual time of the triple execution was less than
          fifteen minutes
          1
          Special to The Evening World
          DANNEMORA Oct tThe lives of the three Van Wormer boys
          p tyho were condemned to death for the murder of Peter Hallenbeck were
          forfeited to the tw In extraordinarily quick time today The ceremony
          1 of shocking them to death in the elecfrtfc chair consumed but thirty sec
          I onds over fifteen minutes That length of time elapsed from the moment
          when y1illis Van Wormer left his cell and started for the death chamber
          until the physicians pronounced Burton Van Wormer the last of the trio
          dead
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1912-08-11/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;q=Victims+Death+Chair+Execution+Electric+Executed+Electricity&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.696,0.055,0.307,0.348,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          9 VICTIMS FOR DEATH CHAIR IN ONE DAY
          NKW YORK. Aug. 10- Twenty-two
          jears ago this week, on August C,
          1890, William Kemmlcr, a condemned
          murderer, was put to death In the
          electric chair In Auburn prison. Kern.
          mler ttas the first victim to be legal
          ly executed by electricity in tb Unit
          ed States and his case was the sub
          ject of wide discussion at the time.
          The action of New York In substitut
          ing the electric chair for the gallows
          has been found generally satisfact
          ory and her example has been fol
          lowed by Ohio, Virginia, South Caro
          lina, Massachusetts, Kentucky auJ
          New Jersey.
          ijlnce the execution of Kemmler
          there hae been 151 persona put to
          death In the electric chair In New
          York. The state prison authorities
          estimate that It costs about J4000 per
          individual to carry, out the capital
          punishment mandate. On the basis
          of Oils estimate New York state haa
          expended about JC3.000 for electro
          cutions since that form of Inflicting
          the death penalty was introduced.
          Several times the electric chair at
          Sing Sing has had two victims in
          one day, and on one occasion a short
          time ago three persons were put to
          death within a period of twenty-four
          hours. Rut never before has there
          been such a wholesale execution of
          death sentences Imposed on prison
          ers In this state as is scheduled to
          take place at Sing Sing next week.
          Nino men are to die on the same
          day, and In as rapid succession H3
          they can be led to the death chair.
          -:ix of the nine prospective victims
          are the Italians who were convicted
          of the atrocious murder of Mrs Mary
          Hall at Croton Id Kit. Westchester
          County, on Nov 9, 1911.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86061215/1915-07-31/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Death+Electric+Chair+Electrocuted+Executed+Execution+Murdered+Rosenthal&amp;r=0.381,0.68,0.585,0.332,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Electric Chair Gets Men Who Murdered Rosenthal
          Three Shocks Given.
          The first shock lasted a full minute
          and the executioner said that it was
          1,850 volts and ten aniperes in
          strength. It came while Becker was
          still commending his soul to his
          niflknr.
          I The two prison physicians stepped
          forward to examine the collapsed flg
          ure that sat supported in the death
          chair by the thick black leather straps.
          The stethoscope was applied to the
          heart and Dr. Charles Farr, the prison
          physician, pressed his finger against
          the artery in the neck. There was
          still a feeble fluttering of the heart.'
          The physician stepped back from
          the rubber mat and again the electric
          current pulsed through the body. The
          shock lasted seven seconds and the
          current was then turned off. After 4
          hasty examination Dr. Farr asked that
          a third shock be given. This lasted
          nve seconds. An examination that
          took several minutes followed. Three
          physicians among the witnesses then
          made an examination and Dr.- Farr at
          5:55 o'clock proriounced Becker dead.
          Writes Last Statement.

          TWO ELECTROCUTED
          IN KENTUCKY JAIL
          Eddyville, Ky., July 30—For the
          third time in the history of Kentucky
          a double electrocution took place this
          morning at 3:30 o'clock at the Eddy
          ville penintiary.
          The firBt to be executed was Turn
          er Graham, Jr., 24, a white man, con
          victed for the killing of R. J. Mc
          Murtry, sheriff of Hardin county. The
          second was William Lane, 25, a negro,
          convicted at Pineville, on a charge of
          killing his wife. Lane was the first
          negro to be executed in Kentucky
          since the adoption of electrocution as
          a means of inflicting the death pen
          alty. Both men passed the night
          calmly and walked unassisted to the
          death chamber.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045389/1916-03-05/ed-1/?sp=48&amp;q=Die+Death+Electric+Chair+Electrocution+Electricity&amp;r=0.18,-0.072,0.594,0.337,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          How it feels to die in the electric chair
          Scientists Have Just Discovered
          Many Secrets Which Have Long
          Puzzled Them in Regard to Death
          by Electric Shock From the Exper
          ience of a Man Who Was Electro
          cuted and Brought
          Back to Life
          WHKN the electric chair was sub
          stituted for the old fashioned
          gallows in New York it was be
          cause it was believed that electrocution
          was painless. But just what were the
          sensations of death in the electric chair
          scientists were unable to say, because
          no electrocuted victim came back to life
          to tell tliern.
          It was assumed that the shock of the
          powerful current would instantly render
          the condemned man unconscious. But
          the unpleasant feature of m^st electro
          cutions has been the necessity of re
          penting the shock several times. This
          was not foreseen
          Experience in ilie death chamber has
          shown that the electric current does
          not usually destroy life at the tirst shock.
          Evidences of pulsating life compel the
          executioner to turn on the current asain
          and yet again. This distressing failure
          of the electric charge to instantly end
          life has caused much speculation among
          scientists and humanitarians.
          Does the first shock end the conscious
          ness of the condemned man?
          Or is the victim siiil conscious?hover
          ing between death and life, does themau
          In the chair realize what is going on?
          What, if any, was the agony of the
          ti rs shock?
          What were the agonies of the victim
          during the moments elapsing between
          tiie tirst shock and the second impact of
          the current? Was he entirely uncon
          scious, partly conscious or fully conscious
          of the horrors of the situation which the
          law never meant to be inflicted on him?
          And if the tirst shock of the current
          benumbed the condemned man's brain,
          did returning consciousness bring with it
          tortures of bodily misery which have
          never been known or suspected?
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030431/1919-08-03/ed-1/?sp=27&amp;q=Deans+Death+Sing+Sings+Tragic+Hour+Electric+Chair+Electricity+Electrocuted+Capital+Punishment&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.133,0.612,0.172,0.195,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Deans of Death Watch Tell of Sing Sing's Most Tragic Hour
          New Tork State had just passed a
          law substituting the electric chair for
          the hangman's noose. There had
          never been an electric execution and
          everybody was prospecting as to who
          would be the first person electrocuted
          and'whether he would bo killed with
          out conscious suffering or tortured to
          death. f
          On October 30, 1889, Warden Brush
          received Charles McElvalne, aged
          twenty, the first person sentenced to
          the electric-' chair., He had- slain
          Christian Lucca In Brooklyn. There
          had been no deathhouse built then.
          So"McElvalne was placed' in a cell on
          the upper floor of tho hospital building
          end kepA In 'solitary conflneme'nt;-' On
          December 5, 1889, work of building tho
          deathhouse was begun. It was to be,
          virtually, a prison within a prison.
          Derrenbachcr saw Thomas Palllster,
          a prisoner, helping to build it. By
          an odd turn of events, this same pris
          oner was later convicted of murder
          and lodged, two years later, in the
          prison death cells himself. He was
          never executed. He cheated the chair
          by escaping,
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038485/1920-09-26/ed-1/?sp=20&amp;q=Electric+chair&amp;r=-0.325,0.429,1.493,0.847,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020097/1931-04-25/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Electric+chair
        </id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025182/1915-07-30/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Electric+chair&amp;r=-0.111,0.65,0.641,0.364,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          "Lord Have Mercy On Me."
          OSININO, N. Y., July 30.-AProtost
          ig bis Innocence to the very last, for
          jer Police Lieutenant Charles Becker,
          H«d In the electric chair at 5:55
          "'clock this morning for- the murder
          1
          Gambler Herman Rosenthal.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045499/1927-11-12/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Electric+chair&r=0.231,0.515,0.596,0.338,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          ELECTRIC CHAIR IS BARBAROUS,
          NOTED DANISH PHYSICIAN HOLDS
          COPENHAGEN, Denmark, Nov
          ^2—Three famous Danish physi
          cians have launched an attack on
          the electric chair, .which they
          t-etm “an American barbarity.”
          ihrfife Toncifi' in thri bqjiof
          'tniit the electric chair 'does' hot
          kill. It merely paralyzes the vie
          tint, the physicians declare, and
          the prison doctor completes the
          execution by failing to revive the
          person shocked.
          Dr. Marius Claudius, chief of
          Urn laboratory of one of Copen
          hagen’s largest hospitals, de
          nounces the electric chair in a'
          article in the journal Polltiken.
          Dr. Viggo Christiansen, famous
          nerve specialist, president of the
          Danish Medical Society, Danish
          government medical counsellor
          and a member of the American
          League of Mental Hygiene, sup I
          ports Dr. Claudius in another arti-
          cle. in which he says:
          "Tho stopping of breathing and
          the heart beat is no sign what
          ever of death. Death rigidity 01
          spots gives the only safe right tc
          declare a mnn dead. Thus in oui
          hospitals nobody must be removed
          from bed before six hours aftei
          the supposed death.
          "Whether the victim suffers af
          tor the electrocution is a hare
          question to answer, but, of course
          there Is iro suffering If the eon
          sciousneSs—which must be sup
          posed—is paralyzed too."
          Dr. Claudius calls death in the
          electric chair "incredible rude
          ness. and executioner work on the
          part of assisting doctors, who b.
          foul their exalted science."
          “To speak of death in tire elec
          tric chair as humane," he writes,
          “is a simple lie. as nobody dies
          in the electric chair. The great
          est authority on electrophysiology.
          Professor Jellinek of Vienna, says
          that electricity never kills, but
          only paralyzes the centers of
          breathing and the it-■art func
          tions. Kven persons hit by light
          ning can be saved if help comes
          in time. Dissection never shows
          any changes in the body causod
          by the current, a»d the electric
          chair therefore only acts like the
          stopping of the pendulum of a
          clock, not spoiling the main work.
          The executioners’ work in Amer
          ica is now really done by physi
          cians.”
          Professor Knud Sand, head of
          the Law-Medical Institute, adds
          his voice of protest.
          "The point is,” he declares,
          “that death by electricity in most
          cases must be considered uncer
          tain. It is absolutely wrong to
          declare a man dead after the elec- J
          trie chair has stopped his breath- j
          ing and heart heat.”
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83004231/1956-02-25/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Electric+chair&amp;r=0.155,0.172,0.649,0.368,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          DIE IN ELECTRIC CHAIR
          Miami’s two most notorious
          criminal characters died in the
          electric chair at the state peni
          tentiary Monday. The Rjjiford
          prison had held them in the death
          house for over a year, but the
          curtain of justice fell before them
          just five days ago.
          George Anderson, th3 pistol
          whipping, slight built, bad man
          and his accomplice in crime,
          Percy Ambrister, walked to the
          mahogony electric chair calmly.
          Limpy chanted a self-composed
          spiritual as he was strapped in
          the death chair, and Wassie Blue’s:
          last words were, “God bless all of
          you.”
          The prison executioner threw
          the switch on the black-hooded
          Limpy at 8:34 and 12 minutes
          later the same death-dealing high
          voltage charge coursed through
          Blue’s body. Beth men were pro
          nounced dead exactly six minutes
          after they got the current, but
          both were crobably dead minutes
          before the doctor placed a steth
          escope over the heart and found
          no sign of life.
          Arrangements were being made
          this week to return the bodies to
          Miami for burial. It is reported
          that Ambrister’Si wife reneged on
          signing the order. Ambrister’s
          immediate family and relatives of
          Andersen were said to be in ac
          cord with the idea.
          After execution the bodies were
          released to a funeral home in
          Starke, for embalming and final
          disposition pending family re
          quests.
          Limpy was 34 years old and
          Wassie Blue 25.
        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>


  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-alaska-purchase/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1867-04-09/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Russian+Russia+Treaty+Empire+Seward&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.479,-0.086,0.596,0.676,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026994/1867-04-12/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Russian+Russia+Treaty+Alaska+gold+mines&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.041,0.11,0.785,0.891,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015486/1867-04-18/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Value+Acquisition+Russia+Russian+Treaty+Treaty+Seward&amp;st=text&amp;r=0,0.062,0.265,0.301,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The Ceded Territory.
          The cesion of Bussian North Ameri
          ca to tbe United States, if consummated,
          will be tbe most important international
          event affecting this continent which bas
          occurred in many years. Snch an unim
          portant part has Bosnian-America played
          in the affairs of nations andof men, that,
          when an offer for its cession from one
          nower to another is made known, the an
          nouncement conjures np in the mind of
          nearly every one visions ol a cold, bar
          ren and uninhabited region, converging
          about Bebringe strait, and celebrated
          only because Capt. Beecby and Sir John
          Fraklin voyaged on its coasts. But in
          this resuscitation of school day memo-
          lies, or even in a casual glance at tbe
          map of the continent itself, the raot im
          portant parts of the territory wonld mot
          likely escape notice. These are the pe
          ninsula of Alaska and the archipelagoes
          known as George 111, and Prince of
          Wnles, rather peculiar names for a series
          of islands forming part of the pos-esnions
          of the Bnstian Bear. It h noticeable,
          however, that tbe Russians kno'v the is
          lands hy other names, and the one nam
          ed George III., by Vancouver, forming
          part of tbe archipelago generally known
          by tlin name of tlMt monarch, fs by them
          called Baranoy. These inlands are form
          ed by inlets of the ocein,- and are more
          properly a narrow strip of land extend
          in for nearly fonr hundred miles along
          tha coast of the Pacific, broken by irn
          row causeways and arms of the sea exten
          dinc iu everv direction.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85034039/1867-05-03/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Russia+Russian+Treaty+Gold+Seward&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.285,-0.079,1.571,1.571,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053571/1867-12-24/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Alaska+Russia+Russian+Treaty+Seward+Sitka&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.001,0.112,0.268,0.305,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          ALASKA
          "It Ilea between the 130th and the UOthdrgreet
          of western longitude, and lying with the ahorea
          of the i roien oeean on the north and the Paclfl
          on the touth, la that broad area of territory newly
          acquired by the American Republic, now desig
          nated by the name of Alaska. It la by far the
          moat northern portion of our national domain.
          Its area In square mllea la not definitely known.
          Moat of the reocraphles put It et.no.000. Mr.
          Sumner thlnka tt la about 6T0.0OO. He la mora
          nearly correct, thouih U maybe 20,0(10 more, or
          perhaps 20,000 less NO American map, aa yet.
          irhes a correct Idea of Ita toDOfi-ranhv,
          arc rlrers aa large ea the Hudson ana Susque-
          iorr
          nnam, nnu iiiduoi rrrnicrarca muminuis
          of Ithode Island, w hlcn hare no name or locality
          on our achool-roora maps."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025293/1868-07-24/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Boundless+Alaska+Russia+Russian+Treaty+Seward&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.104,0.656,0.217,0.246,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>ATTA: NO TEXT AVAILABLE</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053571/1868-07-15/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Alaska&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.017,0.984,0.275,0.312,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The bill appropriating the purchase
          money for Alaska was passed the House
          of Ileprcsentatlvcf, yesterday, by a dcUslve
          ote yeas, 101 J nays, 3 This Is right. Ucn
          rl Hanks has done nobly In this cauat, and
          rough hit energy and perseverance It haa
          !icu carried. He waa warmly congratulated
          y hit frleoda on the triumph of thla met sure.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85054468/1899-07-15/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Golden+Alaska+Alliance+Cape+Nome+Gold&amp;r=0.153,0.8,0.611,0.347,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024828/1899-09-30/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Alaska+Alaskan+Field+Treasure+Cape+Nome+Gold&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.002,0.757,0.283,0.322,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045366/1903-09-12/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=Alaska+Alaskan+Russia+Gold+Cape+Nome+Seward+Present&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.059,0.88,0.233,0.264,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          When Secretary Seward purchased
          Alaska from Russia in 1867 for $7,200,000
          the anti-expansionists of that period ridi
          culed the transaction as a piece of su
          preme folly and the public generally
          agreed that he had bought nothing in par
          ticular except a few fur seals and a vast
          expanse of Icebergs and glaciers.
          The commerce of Alaska for the year
          ending June 30, 1903, amounted to over
          $21,000,000, not including the gold out
          put, which would add nearly $5,000,000
          more.' It is officially stated that since
          Alaska became American territory it has
          exported furs, fish and gold in about equal
          values to the amount of $150,000,000, while
          investments of American capital In Alaska
          have reached $25,000,000.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063778/1921-03-10/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Alaska+Purchase&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.628,0.875,0.224,0.255,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86090528/1901-04-23/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Alaska+Purchase&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.451,0.364,0.208,0.236,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>TRUTH iSOUT AL ASH
          Sacra tarr
          Kaward Said lu
          Acucialtlaw
          Waa Moat Importa
          To the vast majority of i
          ka is a frigid, barren, valm
          of country. It has never si
          Aid!'
          or interest in the hearts and mind
          of tha masses. Doubtless there are
          thousands who cherish the same sen
          timents towards the cold timer that
          were entertained by the opponents of
          the Alaska purchase thirty years ago.
          Congressman Ferris then said that it
          was a "wretched, God-forsaken region,
          with absolutely notning of value"; and
          he moved that the bill authorizing the
          president to pay $7,500,000 for it be
          amended to read "to pay the sum to
          any European. Asiatic or African pow
          er that would take Alaska off our
          hands." Congressman Price declared
          that the payment would be a dead loss
          to the country. Gen Butler proposed
          that, If we must buy the friendship of
          Russia, we give her $7,500,000 and let
          her keep Alaska; and he denounced
          those who favored the acquisition as
          being Insane enough to buy the earth
          quakes of St. Thomas and the Icefields
          of Greenland. Such sentiments, in
          view of the value of Alaska, as at pres
          ent understood by every well-informed
          person, appear almost like the babbling
          of idiocy. We paid 2 cents an acre
          for the territory, the area being 369.
          529,600 acres. The Alaska Fur com
          pany have taken $33,000,000 worth of
          seal skins, and have paid, or owe the
          government $7,340,533 in royalties. It
          Is officially estimated that the Alaska
          fisheries, not including seals and
          whales, are worth $67,890,000, and since
          the purchase the territory has produc
          ed $25,000,000 of gold. Secretary Sew
          ard said that the acquisition of Alaska
          was the most important event in his
          long career, but that It would take a
          generation for the people to realise it.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038485/1923-08-08/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Alaska+Purchase&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.476,0.208,0.266,0.301,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Seward and Alaska
          To the Editor of The Age-Herald:
          Each morning I read “Mothers
          cf Famous Men” and “Poor Boys
          Who Became Fafhous." I enjoy
          both c lumns very much, but very
          often I find that the writers of
          these columns leave out very im
          portant historical facts.
          This morning- under the head of
          “Mothers of Famous Men” was an
          article in regard to the mother
          of William H. Seward, secretary
          of state under Abraham Linoln
          and Lincoln's right hand man. But
          this article failed to say anything
          about the Alaska purchase. Mr.
          Seward was the father of this deal
          and for years before he rose to the
          president’s cabinet he had been a
          champion of the purchase of Rus
          sian America. Like Jefferson,
          Monroe and Livingston, who were
          criticised severely for the pur
          chase in 1803 of Louisiana, known
          as the American Desert, also Se
          ward was severely criticised for
          his efforts to purchase the barren
          stretch of land known as Russian
          America. which today is known as
          Alaska, the richest American pos
          session. Seward's folly proved
          one of the wisest acts in our his
          tnrv
          There 1* a strange similarity in
          the purchases of Louisiana and
          Alaska. Jefferson, Monroe and
          Livingston did not believe that
          they had purchased an empire, but
          i their main object was to eliminate
          a foreign power from our door.
          Seward did not realize that he was
          purhasing an empire when he pur
          chased Alaska; his main object
          was the elimination of a dangerous
          foreign power from our doors.
          But instead both the Louisiana and
          Alaska purchases have proven to
          be America’s richest possessions,
          and eventually Alaska will bo
          thickly settled and will take its
          place with the other section of
          the country industrially, economi
          cally and politically. At present
          still little Is known of Alaska.
          Some writers and newspapers call
          it "America’s Wonderland,” also
          our late president’s visit to our
          Northern empire has revealed
          many valuable and almost un
          known things. But what a pity
          that today very few people ac
          tually know who was responsible
          for the United States of America
          possessing this invaluable terri
          tory.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90061309/1899-09-28/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Alaska+Purchase&st=text&r=-0.051,0.314,1.323,1.323,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          TUB ALASKA PURCHASE.
          In their anti-expansior
          planks the Democrats shouldn't
          leglect to denounce the pur
          chase of that distant and un
          profitable piece of real estate
          iinown as Alaska."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1904-07-17/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Alaska+Purchase&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.28,0.808,0.238,0.27,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>PURCHASE OF THE TERRITORY.
          In 1SE7 Alaska was purchased from Rus
          sia by the United States, and so lightly
          was Its value held that the price paid
          $7,000,000 was generally regarded as being
          partly a present to Russia for her sup
          posed help In the Chil War. In the thirty
          six years since that time the United States
          Government has received back in revenues
          alone from Alaska not only the sum ex
          pended but four million dollars more.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>


  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>